

CONTACT ME AT

• London, SE5 0BB

eokuchukwu95@gmail.com

https://blissful-volhardcef363.netlify.app/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/e mmanuel-okuchukwu-677011b4/

SKILLS SUMMARY

React.js

HTML5, CSS3 and SCSS

Javascript

Bootstrap 4

Styled-Components

Lucidchart

C#

PHP

MYSQL

Microsoft office 365

Good team player

Quick Learner

Excellent Written and Verbal Communication

EMMANUEL OKUCHUKWU

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm an IT Professional with a keen interest in Computer Programming and Web Development. I have experience with JavaScript, I use react.js for client-side and I am currently learning node.js for server side. I have some knowledge on PHP and java. My interests however lie on frontend development using react.js, html, CSS, scss and styled-components. I also have some experience using wireframe design tools like Lucid Chart, draw.io and Axure.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern Web developer

Greenwich Bright G-Wizards | Dec 2017 - Sept 2018

- Initial assessment of the website to understand current problems.
- Led on-going maintenance of the web site using C#, ASP.NET.
- Designed the website user interface using CSS and HTML.

Trainee Database administrator

Light House | Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

- I was involved in the planning and development of the database, as well as in troubleshooting any issues on behalf of the users.
- On-going DBA duties, including maintenance, data entry & data querying.
- Database administration including installation,
- test, start-up, shutdown, administration and housekeeping.

PROJECTS

Student Web App

https://github.com/EmmanuelOkuchukwu/student-appproject

 The student web app was a group peer assessment application designed and implemented using php,
MySQL, html and CSS. The aim of this project was to create a webapplication that could help students record the performance of the other students in their group and to also help the lecturer record the performance of all the groups in his/her class.



CONTACT ME AT

- London, SE5 0BB
- eokuchukwu95@gmail.com
- https://blissful-volhardcef363.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/e mmanuel-okuchukwu-677011b4/

Admin Dashboard

This project is a small admin panel with crud capabilities and basic authentication with jwt that allows users to login. The front-end is react.js and backend is json server. Other additional tools used for this project was simple-reactvalidator for the error handling in the front-end and reactalert for the alert messages.

PatientComms Management System

https://github.com/EmmanuelOkuchukwu/pms-web-ui PCMS is a web application designed and built for the purposes of online communication between a patient and their doctor. This new system will encourage patients to be in constant communication with their clinical practitioner when they do not come in to visit their doctors.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

University of Greenwich

MSc Computing and Information Systems | 2019 - 2020

- Core Modules: Software Tools and Techniques (Java), User Centered Web Engineering (PHP and MySQL) and MSc Project (React and Java).
- Grade: Merit

University of Greenwich

BSc Computing | 2014 - 2017

- Core Modules: Computer programming (Java), Information Analysis (MySQL Workbench), Application and Web Development
- Grade: 2:2

HOBBIES AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

I built a windows 10 PC.

I enjoy reading articles on technology and software engineering.

I enjoy developing web applications in my free time.

I enjoy playing Table tennis.